welcome back to am Northwest here
to share a vintage collection from a
pediatrician's estate Plus offer advice
on what parents can do and what they
should be keeping we welcome back antia
prais or Gary germer great to see you
Gary okay so so while the average person
is not going to have this we a lot of
people do keep so many things from our
children and maybe they're grown out of
the nest all of that what are some tips
for parents were thinking about what to
keep what to toss what to make sure
the kids take well of course obviously
anything's sentimental but as far as
what's going to go up in value what I've
seen consistently throughout the years
is pop culture kids can tend to collect
their childhood so our parents collected
Shirley Temple and cats and Jammer
kids you ask a 25-year-old today no
they have no idea who Shirley Temple was
except maybe a politician had one kid
to say it tell me well he's he was right
yeah and then um and so people tend to
when they get in their 20s and 30s and
into their 40s will'll collect back their
childhood so anything if if your kids
are going off save the toys that are
in excellent condition uh any kind of
music okay videos and whatnot um
oddly enough kids are collecting
and this might be something when you're
cleaning your parents house uh polaroid
pictures oh and and slides the old
slides our parents used to have and the
reason is is because especially if it's
like scenes at the family vacation at a
theme park it's a it's a snapshot of
time sure and so people like to collect
those kinds of things so most anything
that can take people back to a certain
period that they can relate to if
you get much beyond your grandparents
generation then it becomes a history
lesson and you have to research it and so
less less chance to do it now you're
working on this estate of a pediatrician
who passed a while back and there are
some amazing things here i' have never
seen before so show me some of these
just so we can get a hint of History well
we're going to have a sale coming this
weekend and it's I don't know quite this
is maybe 1 to 2% of the collection he
collected anything to do with babies
and and so uh all of this is baby
related and and feeding type of things of
course different generations of bottles
baby bottles as wow look at there some
doll things old antique rattles and
feeders is that what those are yeah
and the teething rings in front they
have a little rattle on them oh wow did
just not to these here are medicine
feeders I can tip it up and you can kind of
see where you'd hold your thumb over
the end that I'm holding right and the
medicine would go inside and you put
your thumb over it it would hold it in
stick it in the baby's mouth let go and
it would go down their throat to make
them take their castor oil or their
medicine wow I was going to try it out on my
cat but it didn't work on him you know
it never works on cats I don't know what
you do about cats that's a whole another
story he was a bottle collector these
are all infant feeders that predate uh
these these are the oldest things and
really the only thing of serious value
on the table are these two these are
infant feeders from about the Revolutionary
War period late 1700s uh transfer
wear it's on on ceramic and whatnot I'm
not quite sure how they cleaned them you
because oh good point you know they're
just they're just uh you know you had to
clean them up okay so this would be
you would fill this up with whatever
was being fed and then it would come
out this way into the baby's mouth right
and you could still kind of use your
thumb to guide how fast it would come out
to if you wanted to but um yeah that's
and that's what these are the glass ones
came out at the end of the 19th century
when everybody was all worried about
everything hygienic there I have like
800 of these wow all from different
companies and they would be like this
you'd put the milk in it here but when you
fed the baby you would have this little
nipple that would go into it oh I see
and of course the rubber pieces never
survived no and so or rarely survived
obviously but but um and that those were
the that was how you fed your babies
before you had baby bottles right wow and
then tell me what are these these like
little teapots or something they're
little they're invalid feeders and so if
you're sick in bed and this is more for
adults it could do children this one is
like with the Red Cross on it or is
World War I era you'd put broth or
some Thin soup or something in there
and so the person who's in bed you could
you could feed him without using the
spoon that would spill it all and those
were those are invalid feeders huh and
who wouldn't want one yeah I don't know
little rum and coke yeah you know something
like that these are they're kind of
cute actually they're kind of a fun
thing and and there's and obviously they
came in all kinds of materials porcelain
metal uh glass yeah what not okay
then tell me about these dishes here
now the baby plates these were all baby
plates at one time every baby had to have
one had the ABC alphabet around it so
the baby could learn that and it would
have a picture on the bottom and part of
the theory was to get the child to eat
his uh porridge you ate down till you
could see your cartoon character at the
bottom of it or your in the story it's
that's funny because there are my husband
has a baby plate from when he was a
baby obviously I I don't have one but
that's not a thing that people do anymore
is it like they have plates for their
babies a commemorative plate I I don't
know I mean I think it's a shower gift
probably but I don't see it as like they
used to use them as much as they did
and they were a fun thing to I think
they're a fun thing to collect um they
make a cute display they're colorful and
they're not expensive I mean um these are
all under everything here is under $50
most of it's under $30 wow and so you
collect it over here and these are all old
um baby for baby formula containers
and how they used to sell you know pum
or whatnot in the different types this
is my favorite it's the one that shows uh
how bone marrow the fat for infants so
it was was full of bone marrow to feed
your child no way yeah wow okay wow
kind of greasy and weird but it was
uh well you know don't hold back don't
hold back your feelings about that one
obviously I I got too much of it when
I was a baby by the way I look now well
let's go back to so the average person
one of the things though is parents tend
to hand hang on to everything that their
kids used while they were growing up
but then it needs to go to that child the
adult child and at some point it seems
like nowadays most adult children don't
want half the stuff minus some of the
toys I think true right true and uh
yeah kids don't see and and part of it I
think is our cultures changed our our
parents well our parents set beautiful
tables and all that and now they don't
do that as much dinner parties and stuff
like that uh but if they will hang on to
their electronics and like I said vinyl
record clth and stuff like that does
sell that that's what they do want and
of course if knew for sure what was going
to be valuable in 30 years I would be
a multi-millionaire but um CU it all
changes with culture sound it sounds like
the parents need to say come and pick
your stuff up in the garage or it goes
into you know and if you're going to sa
if you're going to save stuff save of
course what's obviously what's
sentimental but also what's in excellent
condition because you can have something
that's collectible but if it's beat up
it's worth five bucks if it's in excellent
condition it can be worth a lot of
money yeah absolutely great advice Gary
gmer thank you very much all right we'll